GAURANK PATEL

Cumming, GA 678-754-9675 patelgaurank@gmail.com

Experienced Senior Data Analyst and Full stack developer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. Skilled in Visual Basic script, SQL, T-SQL, Python, VS tool, Visio, API, Web Framework (React, Next.js, and Django), GitHub, Docker, PostgreSQL, SQLite, Microsoft Office, BI Tools and Analytical Skills. Evaluation design and implementation experience; Data analysis experience; Data (e.g. HR, Operational, Finance, Health, Insurance etc.) interpretation experience; Report writing and presentation experience; Program evaluation and providing Technical Assistance (T/A) experience; T/A to funded sites on evaluation skills experience; Both quantitative and qualitative methods; Ability to manage a team, work independently as well as in a team environment and ability to multi-task and possess strong organizational skills; Public health experience or proficiency in understanding complex, sophisticated health sciences topics and strong ability to translate and simplify for various audiences. Ability to resolve conflict and work tactfully and respectfully with a wide variety of experts and outside scholars; and Strong written, oral and interpersonal communication skills with the ability to brief professional and scientific staff on progress/issues.



WORK EXPERIENCE -----

Full stack developer

08/2017 to Present Social Work Cumming, GA

- Developing a Software as a service website (Responsive) for the temple using Djanog RESTApi framework, React/NextJs frontend framework, PostgreSQL database server and Window server. In this project multiple user (Admin, Social worker, and end user) login using two-step authentication, enter sponsor or view historical sponsors, display sponsor data in dashboard and display on projector.
- Developed a frontend (Responsive) and backend application using Django Web framework (which is developed using python) with PostgreSQL database, Redux, HTML, JavaScript and W3Css/Bootstrap/CSS library.
- Developed a backend RESTful/GraphQL API using Django web framework with PostgreSQL. And Frontend (Responsive) using REACT/Next.Js (UI Framework) with MaterialUI (CSS library) and CSS.
- · Using Docker to deploy in Linux system.
- Leading software engineer team in India.

Python Developer Consultant

08/2017 to Present

CyberData Technology Inc.

Atlanta, GA

Providing high level advanced support to client in managing specific issue resolution activities.

- Developed an automation to collect, performed an ETL process and quantitative analysis of complex data, such as Online social data (Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram), Community Health data, Team performance/accomplishment data, and BRFSS/WICPC/NIS analyst data.
- Utilizing programmatic and quantitative methods to identify patterns and relationships in large data sets, as well

- as apply mathematical, statistical, and other data-driven analysis.
- Suggesting solutions for moderate to complex data for internal processes, as well as overseeing crossdepartmental projects as needed.
- Using advanced computer modelling, database tools and/or other approaches in conducting the analysis.

Python Developer Consultant

07/2015 to 07/2017

Northrop Grumman

Atlanta, GA

Providing high level advanced support to client in managing specific issue resolution activities.

- Suggesting solutions for moderate to complex application/data structure for internal processes, as well as
 overseeing cross-departmental projects as needed.
- Developed/suggested an automation to collect, performed an ETL process and quantitative analysis of complex data, such as Online social data (Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram), Community Health data, Team performance/accomplishment data, and BRFSS/WICPC/NIS analyst data.
- Utilizing programmatic and quantitative methods to identify patterns and relationships in large data sets, as well as apply mathematical, statistical, and other data-driven analysis.
- Using advanced computer modelling, database tools and/or other approaches in collecting data and conducting the analysis.
- Providing guidance to junior analysts and brainstorming with the client and teams on approaches or solutions to the complex or lengthy routine method.

Sr. Data Analyst Engineer

02/2012 to 07/2015

United Postal Service

Atlanta, GA

Developed and Maintained Dashboards connecting several data sources to support analytics.

- Identified root causes of recurrent work failure to estimate time and cost to implement new work methods, processes, and flows.
- Recommended design changes to enhance basic work methods.
- Conducts statistical analysis on recent and historical data to identify and compare trends.
- Reviewed projected package volume and actual delivery service data to identify service correlations.
- Monitored the automated processes for various product launches
- Gather individual site activity information to provide the status report for weekly business conference calls.
- Performed data mining and manipulation to assist management with ad hoc reporting and presentations.
- Identified emerging trends to analyze the impact on information retrieval and reporting and to determine standards for report generation, maintenance, and distribution.
- Identified root causes of recurrent work failure to estimate time and cost to implement new work methods, processes, and flows.
- Recommended design changes to enhance basic work methods.
- Reviewed projected package volume and actual delivery service data to identify service correlations.

Python - 6 years

Django Web Framework - 5 years

REACT - 3 years

Next Js - 2 years

JAVA - 1 year

JavaScript - 3 years

JSON - 5 years

Office 365 - 4 years

OBIEE - 3 years

Power BI - 4 years

Power App - 4 years

Power Automation - 4 years

SharePoint - 4 years

BI Tools - 6 years

RESTful API - 5 years

GraphQL - 1 year

AWS - 1 year

Google Cloud - 1 year

IIS - 2 years

PostgreSQL - 3 years

SQL - 7 years

T-SQL - 2 years

SQL Server - 3 years

W3CSS - 4 years

CSS - 4 years

HTML - 4 years

Material UI - 3 years

Selenium - 4 years

SCRUM - 2 years

Agile - 2 years

Responsive website - 5 years

SDLC - 5 years

GitHub - 5 years

CI/CD - 5 years



EDUCATION

Bhavnagar University

Bachelor's Marketing Bhavnagar, Gujarat, India 06/1998 to 04/2001

NIIT

Other
Network - Centered Computing
Bhavnagar, Gujarat, India
08/1998 to 02/2001